Guide to the Morris Schappes Papers TAM.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1911-2004
  - Foner, Jack and Moe, 1976-2000 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Foner, Philip, 1973-1995 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Forward, 1990, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Freedom of Expression at Yale, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 1986 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - French Revolution Bicentennial, 1981-1989 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - French Revolution Bicentennial, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Furriers' Union, 1963-1964 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., 1989-1996 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Gates, John, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Gays, 1986-1987 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Gays, 1988-1992 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Gays, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Gesher:Bridge - Feminist Newsletter of New Jewish Agenda, 1986-1989 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Ginger, Ann Fagan, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Gittelsohn, Roland B., 1983 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Gluck, Sid and Bel Kaufman, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Gold, Doris, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Goldberg, Itche, 1987-1998 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Goldburg, Robert E., Rabbi, 1983, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Goldring, Benjamin, 1990, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Goldstein, Jonah J.: Retirement under Fire, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Gompers, Samuel (and Strasser, Adolph), 1917, 1940, 1950-1959, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Goodman, Carolyn (Goodman, Andrew), 1974 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Gordon, Eric, 1987-1992 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Gorelick, Aaron, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Greenberg, Cheryl: Book Review - "The Undiscovered Paul Robeson: An Artist's Journey, 1898-1939", 2001 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Hacker, David ("Crown Heights"), 1993 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Haiti, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Halpern, Stanley, 1994-1997 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Hansberry, Lorraine, 1972-1980 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Harap, Louis (I), 1955-1999 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Harap, Louis (II), 1955-1999 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Harburg, E. Y. (Yip), 1981 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Hartman, Hershl, 1987-1997 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Headgear Workers, 1946-1989, undated (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - Hebrew Immigrant Aid Society (HIAS), 1958-1981 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1949-1989 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Hertzberg, Arthur, 1983-1993 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Hicks, Granville, 1939-1940, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Hispanics, 1985-1992 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Hiss, Alger, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Hoffman, Abbie, 1981, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Holocaust, 1974-2000 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Holocaust: "The Other Victims: Non-Jews Persecuted and Murdered by the Nazis", 1987 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Home and Hospital of the Daughters of Israel, 1965-1970 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Howe, Irving, 1976-1998 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1950-1988 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Hungary, [1949-1950] (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Hutchinson, Earl Ofari, 1991-1997 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Illustrated Radical Wall Calendar in Yiddish and English, 1923-1924 (Box 46)
  - Immigration Citizenship, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Immigration of Intellectuals, 1953-1985 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Immigration: Various Articles, 1948, 1966-1982 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - International Jewish Peace Union (IJPU), 1987-1992 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), 1933, 1943-1987, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - ILGWU: Commemoration of 1910 Hart Schaffner and Marx Strike, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - ILGWU: Leaflets, 1931-1933, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Israel / 40th Anniversary, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Israel and Commemorative Stamp - Thomas Edison, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - "Israel and the Evolution of United States Foreign Policy," Eugene V. Rostow, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Israel, the Middle East and Zionism, 1948-2002, undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Israel / South Africa, 1971-1981 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Italian and Jewish Americans, 1972; 1976-1978 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - James Aronson Award for Public Conscience Journalism, 1988-1994 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Japan and Jews, 1987-1992 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Jefferson, Thomas and Sally Hemmings, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Jewish Cultural Writing Contest (Dora Teitelboim Center for Jewish Culture): Submissions, [1997] (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Jewish Cultural Writing Contest (Dora Teitelboim Center for Jewish Culture): Winning Entries and Related Materials, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Jewish Daily Forward, 1917-1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Daily Forward, 1948-1989, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Defense League (JDL), 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Defense League (JDL), 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Defense League (JDL), 1971 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Defense League (JDL), 1972-1991 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Jewish History, Atlanta GA: Shineman, Arnold, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles (Photocopies of 1872-1899 Articles), undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles (Photocopies and Reprints, 1900-1939), undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1944-1959 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1960-1969 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1973-1975 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1981-1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1983-1987 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Articles, 1996-1999, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Notes, 1955-1986, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Notes (I), undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Notes (II), undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Notes (III), undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Jewish History: Background/Research - Notes (IV), undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Jewish History, California: Correspondence, Clippings, 1940-1990 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Jewish History, California: Research, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Jewish History, California: Strauss, Levi, 1939-1954 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Jewish History: "Chapters in American Jewish History" American Jewish Historical Society - Chapters 1-79, 1997-1998 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Jewish History: "Chapters in American Jewish History" American Jewish Historical Society - Chapters 80-141, 1998-2000 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Jewish History: "The American Jewish Farmer", American Jewish Archives Exhibit, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Jewish History: Settlement in Clarion, Utah (Kristol, Ben), 1968, 1987, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Jewish History: "Some Attitudes of the East European Jewish Immigrants towards Organized Jewish Charity in the U.S., 1890-1900" - Excerpts (Photostat), 1934 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Jewish History: Syllabi and Bibliographies, 1939, 1948-1950 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Jewish History: Syllabi and Bibliographies, 1954-1955, 1971-1976 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture, 1947-1979 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture, 1981-2000, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture: Background and Course Materials (I), [1913]-1963 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture: Background and Course Materials (II), [1913]-1963 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture: Background and Course Materials (III), [1913]-1963 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Identity and Culture: "Jewish Race and German Soul in 19th Century America" - Nadel, Stanley, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Labor Bund, 1945-1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Labor Bund: Hirsh Lekert, 1938-1967, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Labor Bund: Hirsh Lekert, 1975-1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1947-1955 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research, 1942-1959, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research, 1945, 1961-1986 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research, 1971-1984, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - "Jewish Labor-II", 1945-1952, undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - "Jewish Labor-III", 1952, 1958, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - "Jewish Labor-V" and "Jewish Labor-VI", undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - "Jewish Labor-VIII" and "Jewish Labor-IX", 1945-1953, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - Moses Levy and the Cordwainers' Case, 1931, 1954, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Jewish Labor History: Background/Research - R. L. Ziv, 1900, undated (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Life, 1946-1957, undated (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - "Jewish Life in America: Fulfilling the American Dream": NYPL Exhibit, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Music Alliance, 1958-1959 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Jewish National Fund, 1946-1947, undated (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Peace Lobby, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order (JPFO)/International Workers Order (IWO), 1932, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order (JPFO)/International Workers Order (IWO), 1947-1951 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order (JPFO)/International Workers Order (IWO), 1952-1964, undated (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Jewish Radicalism, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Jewish Socialist Critique, 1978-1980 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Jewish Socialist Federation, 1939-1954 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Jewish Women's Committee to End the Occupation, 1988-1992 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Jews for Racial and Economic Justice, 1991-1995 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Judaism, 1947-2002 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Jurist, Elliot, 1986-1989 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Kahane, Meir, 1986-1990 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre (Article from New World Review), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Katz, Elaine and Lyber, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1983-1993 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Korczak, Janusz (Henry Goldszmit): "Janusz Korczak: between Two Worlds", Moshe Shner, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Korn, Bertram W., 1962-1980 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Kramer, Aaron, 1984-1997 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Kramer, Aaron, 1988-1997 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Kramer, Aaron: Correspondence, "A Ballad of August Bondi" and "Moses", 1955, 1958, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Kriegel, Leonard, 1982-1994 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Krummel, Regina, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Kunstler, William, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Landsmanschaften, 1945-1948, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - LaRouche, Lyndon H., 1986 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Centenary Year Clippings, Flyers and other Materials, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Lazarus, Emma: "Emma Lazarus Rediscovered", 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Lazarus, Emma: "Emma Lazarus Rediscovered" - Notes, Flyer, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Emma Lazarus: Selections from her Poetry and Prose Edited, with an Introduction, by Morris U. Schappes, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Emma Lazarus: Selections from her Poetry and Prose - Correspondence, Clippings, Copyright and Related Material, 1944, 1966-1968, 1980-1988 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Lazarus, Emma: "Emma Lazarus, Singer and Spokesman of the Semites", Morris U.Schappes, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews Centennial Edition, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews - Copy (Annotated) and Notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews - Copy, Correspondence, Edited Typescript and Notes, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews - Galleys, 1986-1987 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews, Introduction and Notes - Drafts, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Lazarus, Emma: An Epistle to the Hebrews, Introduction and Notes - Galleys, 1985 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The Letters of Emma Lazarus, from 1868 to 1885... - Annotated Typescript, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The Letters of Emma Lazarus, from 1868 to 1885... - Publication and Clippings, 1949, 1950, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The Letters of Emma Lazarus, from 1868 to 1885... - Research Notes, Correspondence, Transcriptions (I), 1949 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The Letters of Emma Lazarus, from 1868 to 1885... - Research Notes, Correspondence, Transcriptions (II), 1949 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The Letters of Emma Lazarus, from 1868 to 1885... - Research Notes, Correspondence, Transcriptions (III), 1949 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Morris Schappes Interview Transcript, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Photographs and Photostats (late 19th century), undated (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Photostatic Copies of Lazarus Letters, undated (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence, 1975, 1980-1985 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Lazaris, Vladimir, 1981-1990 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Lazaris, Vladimir, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Peck, Abraham J., 1983 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Pollack, Herman, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Sarna, Jonathan D., 1983 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Young, Bette Roth, 1982-1994 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Related Correspondence - Young, Bette Roth, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Lazarus, Emma: "Reply to Sally Prudhomme" - Notes and Publication in The Magazine of American History... (January 1882), undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Script for Radio / Television, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Sheet Music - "Give Me Your Tired, Your Poor", Berlin, Irving, [1949] (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Stage Plays, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Statue of Liberty Centennial - Articles, Correspondence, Notes, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Television Documentary Proposal - "Emma Lazarus: A Song for Liberty", 1985 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Translated Letters to E.R.A. Seligman (1883), undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Various Articles, Press Releases, Notes, Clippings, Advertisements, 1944-1956, 1978-1997, undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Various Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Various Notes, 1985, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Various Research Articles (Photocopies of Articles [1846]-1944), undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Various Research Notes and Materials, 1948-1952, undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Lazarus, Emma: "Who Is the 'Mother of Exiles'? An Inquiry into Emma Lazarus' 'The New Colossus,'" Daniel Marom, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Lazarus, Emma: The World of Emma Lazarus by H. E. Jacob - Reviews, Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Lazarus, Emma: Zionism, Correspondence with E. R. A. Seligman and Related Materials, 1988, undated (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Lehrman, Leonard and Nathaniel, 1964-1988 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Lehrman, Leonard and Nathaniel, 1989-1999 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Lemisch, Jesse, 1969-1971 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Lengyel, Cornel, 1971-1972 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Lerner, Michael (Tikkun), 1993 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Lester, Julius, 1968-1990 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Levin, Michael, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Levine, Phillip, 1979-1988 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Levy, Hyman, 1958-1975 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Lewinsky, Monica, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Liebman, Arthur: "Jews and the Left" (I), 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Liebman, Arthur: "Jews and the Left" (II), 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Linguistics: Soviet Controversy (Including Concerning Marxism in Linguistics, Joseph Stalin), 1950-1954 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Literature: Various Articles, 1945-1986 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Lubavitcher Movement: Critique by Allan Nadler, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Lubin, Siegmund, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Lumer, Hyman, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - McCloy, John, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Mailer, Norman, 1982-1991, undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Malamud, Bernard, 1963-1974 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1945-1946 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Maltz, Albert, 1972-1985 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Mancan, Sherry: "Introduction to Snow", 1978 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Marcus, Jacob R., 1977-1994 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism, 1946-1949 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism, 1950-1959 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism, 1962-1969 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism, 1970-1979 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism, 1980-1983, undated (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Marx, Karl: Anti-Semitism - Notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Maxwell, Robert, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - The Merchant of Venice / Shylock: Anti-Semitism, 1962-1969 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - The Merchant of Venice / Shylock: Anti-Semitism, 1970-1974 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - The Merchant of Venice / Shylock: Anti-Semitism, 1980-1995 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Meskin, Ed, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Michoels, Solomon, 1943 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Miller, Arthur, 1983-1987, 2000 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Mizel, Gary, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Mizel, Gary, 1990-1992 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Molly Maguires, 1948, 1964-1980 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Morning Freiheit, 1945, 1987-1991 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Morning Freiheit (I), 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Morning Freiheit (II), 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Morning Freiheit (III), 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Morning Freiheit (IV), 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Morning Freiheit (V), 1947-1955 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Moscow Trials Campaign Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - "The Moscow Trials: Statement by American Progressives", 1938 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - "Mussolini and Fascism: The View from America," John P. Diggins: Excerpts, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - National Association of Jewish State Legislatures, 1978, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - National Survey of American Jews, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1981-1982 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - New Alliance Party, 1987-1990 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - New Alliance Party, 1991-1993, undated (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - New Amsterdam: Research Notes, Articles, Correspondence, Postcards, 1976-1980, undated (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - New German Critique, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Nigeria, 1995-1998 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1973 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Notes: Various, 1954-2002, undated (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Obituaries: Various, 1967-1990 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Odets, Clifford, 1952-1973 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Oliver Twist, 1951 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Ornitz, Samuel, 1951-1957 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Osheroff, Abe, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 31)
  - Overman Hearings on German and Russian Propaganda: Transcripts (includes Testimony of Louise Bryant and John Reed), 1919 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Overman Hearings on German and Russian Propaganda: Transcripts (Includes Testimony of Louise Bryant and John Reed) - Carbon, 1919 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Palestinian Refugees: United Nations Material, 1966 (Box 34A, Folder 1)
  - Paull, Henry, [1947] (Box 34A, Folder 2)
  - Paull, Irene, 1971-1996 (Box 34A, Folder 3)
  - Pen and Hammer Club, 1934-1935 (Box 34A, Folder 4)
  - People of the State of New York vs. the International Workers Order, Inc.: Settlement, 1951 (Box 34A, Folder 5)
  - People's Congress for Democracy and Peace, 1937 (Box 34A, Folder 6)
  - A Pictorial History of the Jews in the United States: Annotated Volume, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - A Pictorial History...: Annotated Volume - Enclosed Notes, Clippings, Correspondence (I), 1970-1994, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - A Pictorial History...: Annotated Volume - Enclosed Notes, Clippings, Correspondence (II), 1970-1994, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1890-1900 (I), 1955-1982, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1890-1900 (II), 1955-1982, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1890-1900 (III), 1955-1982, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1930-1939 (I), 1930-1938, 1962-1978 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1930-1939 (II), 1930-1938, 1962-1978 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1930-1939 (III), 1930-1938, 1962-1978 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - 1930-1939 (IV), 1930-1938, 1962-1978 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - "Chapter 10. The New Century and the New Labor Heroism" (I), 1961-1985, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (II), 1961-1985, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (III), 1961-1985, undated (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (IV), 1961-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (V), 1961-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (VI), 1961-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 10. (VII), 1961-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - "Chapter 11. War, Revolution, Reaction and Prosperity" (I), 1918-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 11. (II), 1918-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 11. (III), 1918-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 11. (IV), 1918-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 11. (V), 1918-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. "The Fateful Decades: 1930-1950" (I), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. (II), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. (III), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. (IV), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. (V), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 12. (VI), 1933-1985 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 13. "Mid-Century Profile" (I), 1952-1978 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - A Pictorial History...: Background/Research - Chapter 13. (II), 1952-1978 (Box 37, Folder 2)